Overview

With 10 years plus of experience in **Marketing, client relations and operations**, I have developed a strong skill set that includes in-depth understanding of **Business Management**, optimization of existing **Customer relationship**, Innovative approach towards day to day business problems.

An urge to achieve perfection at every assigned task & a can do attitude help me in achieving targets that seem hard to achieve. With the help of natural leadership qualities I lead teams to achieve their mutual & individual goals. My key areas of expertise are in good interpersonal skills, business development, business planning, performance analysis & ability to work with a team and lead a team.

Work Experience

December 2012 – Till Date: "Percept OOH"

Designation: Key Accounts Director

Duties & Responsibilities:

Business Development

- To generate revenue from new business development.
- Responsible for identifying new event opportunities within the existing Clients.

Marketing & Communication

- Develop innovative marketing ideas for clients.
- Conceptualize new events for the existing clients.
- To establish close collaboration with industry associations & government departments for their active **Ensure brand consistency** to highest standard.

May 2012 - December 2012: FINEDGE India PVT Ltd

Designation: Sr. Manager - CTOF Events

Duties & Responsibilities:

Business Development

- To generate revenue for the CIO Events under the banner of CTO Forum / CIO & Leader Magazine.
- Responsible for identifying new event opportunities within the IT & Telecom Clients.
- To generate revenue from **print advertisement** as well as online space selling & webinars.
- Execute lead generation campaign in support with the **advertisement sales team**.

Marketing & Communication

- Develop innovative ideas for promoting IT Companies.
- Conceptualize new events for the CTOF Brand.
- To conceptualize and execute multi city CXO Round-Table Conferences and utilize the platform to connect with the industry stalwarts.
- To establish close collaboration with industry associations & government departments for their active participation and information dissemination.
- Conduct post event campaign analysis and provide feedback for sponsor debriefs and future sponsor proposals and also prepare competitor updates for marketing, conference and sponsorship purpose
- Ensure brand consistency to highest standard.

August 2007 – May 2012: "OMI" - LAQSHYA Media Pvt Ltd

Designation: Manager

Duties & Responsibilities:

Business Development

- To **generate revenue** for the Exhibition & Conference happens annually in Kolkata under the banner of Businessworld Magazine.
- Responsible for identifying new conference opportunities within defined industries and market segments; includes researching potential markets.
- Execute **lead generation** campaign in support with the advertisement sales team.

Marketing & Communication

- Develop innovative ideas for **promoting the events**.
- To conceptualize and execute multi city CXO Round-Table Conferences and utilize the platform to promote events and also connect with the industry stalwarts.
- To conceptualize and execute various special features in the in-house publications i.e. The Businessworld Magazine, the Telegraph & Ananda Bazar Patrika.
- To formulate a plan to utilize both the promotional activities (CXO Roundtables & Print Features) to be a revenue generating model for the SBU.
- To establish close collaboration with industry associations & government departments for their active participation and information dissemination.
- Conduct post event campaign analysis and provide feedback for sponsor debriefs and future sponsor proposals and also prepare competitor updates for marketing, conference and sponsorship purpose
- Ensure brand consistency to highest standard.

Achievements

- Conceptualized and successfully executed The National Telecom Award
- Formulated the idea to organize *The Mobile Expo*.
- Conceptualized the idea of NeGP

Participated in conceptualizing successful properties like *Media & Entertainment Award* Businessworld Telecom Forum.

July 2006- August 2007: "MUDRA"

Designation: Project Manager

Duties & Responsibilities:

Business Development

- To generate revenue.
- Constructing business plans and forecasts, monitoring of business performance, benchmarks and analysis including logistics and budgetary planning.
- Creating opportunities for international & domestic clients to explore markets and get fresh business.
- Liaising with industry & chambers of commerce in countries like Singapore & China through familiarization trips to generate potential business markets and leads.
- Generating leads from domestic markets in support with the various industry bodies.
- Maintaining relations with existing clients and developing new ones.

Marketing & Communication

- Coordination with Corporate Communications department for preparation of marketing & promotional collaterals for events like brochures, flyers, posters, newspaper & journal advertisements.
- Forming alliances with various international trade and industry specific associations & journals for co-promotion activities and barter deals.
- To conceptualize and execute various special events to help exhibitors to connect with the end users & buyers.
- Monitoring service contractor operations to ensure contract compliance.
- On-site servicing of client needs.

Achievements

- Conceptualized an international solar event The *Solar Tech India 2007* under the banner of ELCOMP which is currently known as *Renewable Energy India*.
- Formulated the idea to organize *The Buyer's Village* an exclusive buyer seller meet platform to encourage business development for the exhibitors.

July 2004 - July 2006: Infocom Entertainment Networks

Designation: Assistant Manager - Sales & Marketing

Duties & Responsibilities:

Business Development

- Responsibilities included Business Development for the company.
- Conceptualizing innovative ideas for pitching new clients.
- Understanding clients brief and then further discuss with the creative team to formulate a constructive event.
- Conducted Product Launches, Brand Promotion Activities, Road Shows, Dealers Meet, Fashion Shows & Artist Management.

Marketing & Communication

- Coordination with the creative department for on time delivery of the project concept to the client.
- Monitoring vendor operations to ensure quality & on time delivery of the commitment.
- On-site servicing of client needs.
- Monitoring and analyzing existing customer requirements.
- Coordinating with leading consumer durable companies to understand their upcoming launches and develop new business relationships.

Achievement

• Conceptualized events like *King of the Kings* for a top level dealers meet for HCL which was a grand success and my efforts where appreciated by the top officials of HCL.

July 2003 - July 2004: Candid India

Designation: Executive - Sales & Marketing

Duties & Responsibilities:

- Responsibilities included, Internet Marketing for a NRI Portal Indians Living Abroad.
 Com.
- Business Development & Tour Management for an online travel company- Pick Your Trip. Com.

July 2002 - January 2003: Mind Care Foundation of India

Designation: Project Executive

Duties & Responsibilities:

Responsibilities included business development for the MTNL Perfect Health Mela.

Academic Qualifications

- Passed Class XII, Board ICSE Year 2000
- Passed Class X, Board ICSE Year 1998
- Bachelor in Business Administration {2000 03} From Madras University
- Post Graduate Diploma in Marketing & Sales {2003 04} From Lucknow University.
- MBA from Cambridge University{2004 06}

Professional Qualifications

- Diploma in Multimedia from Aptech.
- Working Knowledge of MS Office & Latest Window Software.
- Working Knowledge of Internet.